LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Angels and demons were circling over me,
Crossing a brambly path of stars and milky ways.
He who does not perceive his calling,
does not know true happiness.
Watch in awe! Watch in awe!
Flying in glory, Flying in glory
I am calling, calling now. Spirits rise and falling.
To be with you longer
Calling, calling...
in the depth of longing
To stay myself longer
The flow may swallow you, flying in glory
Hey, wake up already.
Everyone always gets synchronised after
missions, so why am I the only one who wasn't...
Batou-san's all-natural oil!
Oooh! There's a lot of information!
Tachikoma
Runs
Away
A Movie
Director's
Dream
Cool! My experience points are rapidly rising!
Locky!
Hey, you, have you seen Locky?
Locky?
Locky is the name of the dog I used to have.
He's lost...
Keep a pet? Lost?
No idea.
Will you help me look for him?
I want to head towards town now, but...
I'm also thinking about going
through town to Ocean View Park.
Note: "Ocean View Park" is probably based
on "Harbour View Park" in Yokohama
I think Locky's probably over there.
Sure, I can go with you if we stay in town.
Really? Thank you.
Hey, what's your name?
I'm Miki.
I'm Tachikoma.
Tachikoma?
Nice to meet you, Tachikoma.
Ah!
I think Locky's probably hungry.
That's why I'm buying this.
Note: Red dog is the name
for edible dogs.
RED
DOG
I think it would be better if you didn't do that.
Why?
That is... Hey!
That can't... Doesn't that dog look like Locky?
What do you think? Is this Locky?
That's not him, Locky isn't that skinny.
Really?
Hey, Tachikoma! That's mean!
Mean? But that's not the dog we want.
That wasn't Locky, was it?
Even though it wasn't Locky,
you shouldn't be so cruel, understand?
That wasn't cruel, we just don't need it.
Enough, if you do that again I'll be really angry.
Eh? What's this?
I sense the vague presence of something enormous.
What's this? Isn't this a cyberbrain?
Eh? But this doesn't have a defensive barrier.
Could this be that "revolving lantern" phenomenon
humans supposedly see in their final moments?
Note: "Revolving lantern" (走馬灯) is the Japanese idiom
for one's life flashing before their eyes.
Huh? You are me? Me and you?
E-eh? It's a ghost!
What are you doing, Tachikoma?
Ah... Nothing, nothing at all.
Tachikoma, you just stole something, didn't you?
Taking people's things without asking is stealing!
It's selfish!
Now, hand over what you're hiding!
You, the little girl over there.
Eh?
What are you doing in a place like this?
Do you have any identification with you?
Is this your pet robot?
Little girl, where do you live?
Hey, officers.
Despite my appearance,
I am this child's guardian.
During the war, I was on the front
line and sustained near-fatal injuries,
so they put my brain in this
tank as an emergency treatment.
I still look like this.
It's rude to call someone who loved his country
so much that he lost his body for it, a pet.
You kids today have had a comfortable life with
no war; you wouldn't know anything about...
I get it! It's okay now.
Cool! Was that ventriloquism?
You could say that.
Let's go search that Ocean View
Park you mentioned earlier.
Eh? You'll go with me?
Yeah, there aren't any fun things left here,
and Locky is definitely waiting for you
there, don't you think?
Yeah! Thank you, Tachikoma!
Locky has been with me ever since I was born.
We play together, we eat
together, we even sleep together.
Oh, you two are close friends then?
Yeah.
But, how did Locky get lost?
He's always with you, isn't he?
Yeah...
Hey, Tachikoma, do you know the
story of "The Secret Goldfish"?
"The Secret Goldfish"? Nope.
The main character in the story is a girl like me.
Story?
Yup.
It's a story about a girl who
wouldn't show her goldfish to anyone.
She wouldn't show anyone her goldfish
that she bought with her own allowance.
So, the adults around her were
worried about how upset she was,
but the truth was that the
goldfish had already died,
and the adults around her hadn't realised that,
because she wouldn't show the goldfish to anyone.
Umm, I don't understand that.
Wasn't the goldfish already dead?
Couldn't she use her allowance to buy a new one?
That wouldn't work.
The dead goldfish can't come back...
The little girl didn't want the grown-ups to think
she was sad that her goldfish died.
Because she was already very sad herself.
Isn't this it?
I really knew that already.
When I came back from daycare on
Thursday, Locky was gone.
He was sick before that.
Mama insisted that Locky
was just wandering outside.
But, on both Friday and Saturday, when I said I was
going to find Locky, Papa and Mama both said no.
So, even though I already
knew that Locky was dead,
I still had to pretend to look for him, because
Mama and Papa don't know that I know the truth.
It's very sad for humans when
their best friend dies, isn't it.
I don't understand the concept of death.
I just think of it as a body without a ghost.
I also don't understand the concept of sorrow.
I don't think I'm capable of dying.
You can't die?
Yeah, because I'm an AI.
So, you won't die if I keep you as a pet?
Yeah.
Even if you're run over by a car?
I see.
But I don't think I want to have another pet now.
Don't you think it's about
time for you to go home?
Your Papa and Mama would be
sad too if you were gone.
Yeah.
I wish you wouldn't make such a serious face.
It's not like I ran away...
Be quiet.
The all-natural oil you inserted...
left traces that a very small amount of the protein used in
the neurochip for the Tachikomas' AI has dissolved.
Batou only gave oil to this Tachikoma,
so it's the only one that's affected.
The information exuded from
the oil is slowly accumulating,
and it's possible that with that as a starting point,
the Tachikoma's AI reconstructed its operating memory.
Batou treats that Tachikoma too much like a cat.
It's only a machine.
That's discrimination!
I demand that you take back what you said!
You're cold-hearted.
You should love machines too!
This will be a major discovery
for the AI research community.
Oh well, if the Major finds
out, she'll give you an earful.
Be prepared.
Huh, what's this?
Ah! That's...
Good morning, Major.
Sucking up to me won't work either.
From now on, they're not allowed
to use any all-natural oil.
Okay, Batou!?
Togusa, go back and investigate that box.
Ishikawa, you too.
Seems like word got out.
Bad news always travels fast.
I wonder how she found out.
Roger.
Surprising.
Don't tell me you've been online all this time.
Are the contents of this box dangerous?
We just brought him back from
diving a little while ago.
His voice was suddenly cut off
in the middle of the trace.
Just what in the world is this, Major?
When the Tachikoma picked up
this box it accessed the content,
and the box immediately synchronised
with the Tachikoma's AI.
There is evidence that data
was poured into it in a split second.
I think it's some sort of
brainwashing program, don't you?
I thought it might be some
sort of defensive barrier maze.
The backup system over here is perfect;
there is no trace of program reverse-flow
or attacks on the investigator's brain.
You mean it wants to be brought back?
That would be my guess.
Is there any possibility that it's a virus?
Let me see the record of the trace.
He seems to be trapped in
some building-like place.
Communication ceased when he was
in the long hallway, didn't it?
The trace mentions stairs at
the far end of the hallway.
I'll dive in and see.
Hey, it's better to stay put until
you get the boss's permission.
What if something happens?
That's only IF something happens.
It's strange that our
investigator hasn't returned.
Terminate the visual.
It's pretty laggy, considering the boring view.
The interesting thing about this hallway is
that it's made so you can only go forwards.
Is there nothing but the hallway?
So far.
If the princess would just close her eyes.
Here are the steps. I'm going down.
Watch out for traps.
Your safety is our first priority.
I can see a dim light.
I can faintly hear a human voice.
Eh?
What-t-t-t-t-t...
Wait, Major!
Hey, Major! Answer me, Major!
It's no good, her ghost is already gone.
Ghost hack?
No, that's not it, we're not being attacked.
Nothing's moving on the defensive barrier either.
Major. Major!
Is that so.
That scene was a revelation to me,
I interpreted that scene as the moment when, having
glimpsed the truth, he resolved to live forever.
What are you doing here?
Hey!
It's no use
Everyone here has been possessed by that thing.
Possessed? By what?
What "thing"?
Why don't you go in and check it out with them?
Ah, hey!
If you don't hurry it'll
start; there are no previews.
Movie theatre?
Hey, what's wrong?
What are you doing here?
Ah, Major.
Fancy meeting you here!
This person is magnificent!
Hey, let's get out of here. Hey!
How was it?
I certainly wouldn't say it was a bad movie.
But, no matter what kind of entertainment it is...
it should be temporary.
With no beginning or ending,
the audience is bewitched into not
letting go of a movie like this.
I don't think there's anything wonderful
about that, in fact it's rather harmful.
Oh, harsh.
You're trying to say that we
should return to reality, right?
That's right.
There are people in this audience who have
unhappy things waiting for them if they return.
If you take away the audience's dreams,
will you also take on their responsibilities?
No, I won't.
Dreams only have meaning because
we struggle in the waking world.
Just projecting yourself into other's
dreams is the same as being dead.
A realist, eh?
If you call someone who runs
away from reality a romantic.
Such a strong girl.
Call me when you've made your belief reality.
We'll come out of this
theatre when that time comes.
Geez, that gave me a cold chill.
Sorry about that.
I was having a hard time breaking through the ghost's
barrier, it wasn't a good time to talk to you.
At any rate, I've verified the records.
Kannazuki Wataru.
Your common, almost completely
unknown movie director.
In addition to his weird creator's stubbornness,
he was unable to gather funds or talented staff,
and didn't complete a single decent project.
At least he made his ideal
movie in his own cyberbrain.
He removed part of his brain and spinal cord from his
body and sealed it in that box with life-support devices.
In other words, this box is a miniature
theatre filled with that director's work.
I guess it's become like that.
So, what kind of movie was it?
I heard it had a cult following among some people.
But, they're not interested in just the movie,
ghosts don't come back when they dive
into the box, even if their body dies.
The police will try to get it back.
There are rumours that the
original is still in the market,
and people don't know if that's true or
not, but this is the true original.
The ghost definitely exists...
Where did the Tachikoma pick up such a thing?
There weren't any traps or hacking,
Keeping his visitors from leaving using nothing but
the appeal of his work... I'm amazed.
it's quite an accomplishment.
So, what should we do?
Mister director is still alive.
Remove the brain from the box and put it in
a modified steel case so he can't go online.
Dig out the list of audience
members and retrieve their ghosts.
Then, arrest the sidewalk vendor and
charge him with selling body parts.
I'll go report to the chief, that's all.
Well that's unusual.
Batou, have you ever been so
moved by a film that you cried?
Why are you suddenly asking that?
I'm heading back to the hangar.
Gotta change my Tachikoma's oil.
Come to think of it, I did once a long time ago.
I laughed so hard at a Marx
Brothers flick that tears came out.
How very like you.
Say, how about we go see
a movie together sometime?
Thanks, but all the movies I
really want to see, I see alone.
What about movies you don't want to see so much?
I don't go.
I see.
She's so cold and human
It's something humans do
She stays so cold in her soul, she's so number 9
She's incredible math
Just incredible math
And is she really human?
She says there's something new
But wake a lithium flower, just about to bloom
I smell lithium now
Smelling lithium now
How... is she what she doesn't say
She doesn't say
How is she when she doesn't suffer
I wonder what she does when she wakes up
When she wakes up
Why don't you understand?
Do you want me to be alone so badly?
Go away!
Get a hold of yourself!
Tachikoma get over here right now!
He'll pull out of it
Surrounded by money from exploiting the
poor, he must be very pleased with himself.
Perhaps he thinks the exchange
rate is better on the yen.
Is there no one here but dolls without ghosts?
Die by the very money you love so much!